<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Zhihao Offline Site</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Zhihao Offline Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Get a Theorem Named after You</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/how-to-get-a-maths-theorem-named-after-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/how-to-get-a-maths-theorem-named-after-you/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I read a funny 3*3 alignment chart of mathematicians and I&amp;rsquo;d like to develope and share it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you ask these people, &lt;em&gt;How to Get a Theorem Named after You:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/posts/how-to-get-a-maths-theorem-named-after-you/DND_chart_of_mathematicians.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DND_chart_of_mathematicians&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here are some explanations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kurt Gödel&lt;/strong&gt;. He is renowned for his &lt;em&gt;Gödel Incompleteness Theorem&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Augustin-Louis Cauchy&lt;/strong&gt;. Bolzano introduced &lt;em&gt;Cauchy sequences&lt;/em&gt; first. Later Cauchy gave a proof,&#xA;taking the nested interval principle, which was later justified by Cantor, as obvious.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carl Friedrich Gauss&lt;/strong&gt;. Around 1800 Legenre published his formula to approximate the distribution of prime numbers. In 1894 Gauss wrote to Encke saying that he had found a better formula in 1793. It turned out that Gauss&amp;rsquo;s formula was more accurate and the form was simpler. It is called &lt;em&gt;Gauss Prime Number Formula&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Prime Number Theorem (PNT)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Georg Friedrich Bernhard Riemann&lt;/strong&gt; When proving &lt;em&gt;Riemann Mapping Theorem&lt;/em&gt;, Riemann used his tutor Dirichlet&amp;rsquo;s work as an assumption, which was found wrong by Hilbert.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Girolamo Cardano&lt;/strong&gt;. In 1539, Tartaglia found the solution to cubic equations of certain kinds. Hearing about this, Cardano started to write to him and their letter conversation lasted 3 months. Finally Caradano promised to keep the formula a secret and Tartaglia gave him it. In 1545, Cardano&amp;rsquo;s book Ars Magna (or The rules of algebra) came out, in which he published the solutions to the cubic equation and the quartric equation, the latter one was found by his assitant Ferrari.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pythagoras&lt;/strong&gt;. (Everyone knows &lt;em&gt;Pythagoras Theorem&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;l&amp;rsquo;Hôpital&lt;/strong&gt;. (Everyone knows &lt;em&gt;L&amp;rsquo;Hopital&amp;rsquo;s Rule&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jules Henri Poincaré&lt;/strong&gt;. (Everyone knows &lt;em&gt;Poincaré&amp;rsquo;s Conjecture&lt;/em&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;Poincaré Theorem&lt;/em&gt; proved by Perelman.)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pierre Fermat&lt;/strong&gt; （Too chaotic, too evil, &lt;em&gt;Fermat&amp;rsquo;s Last Theorem&lt;/em&gt;.）&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Regularity in Differential Geomotry</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/%E5%85%B3%E4%BA%8E%E5%BE%AE%E5%88%86%E5%87%A0%E4%BD%95%E4%B8%AD%E6%AD%A3%E5%88%99%E7%9A%84%E7%90%86%E8%A7%A3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/%E5%85%B3%E4%BA%8E%E5%BE%AE%E5%88%86%E5%87%A0%E4%BD%95%E4%B8%AD%E6%AD%A3%E5%88%99%E7%9A%84%E7%90%86%E8%A7%A3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;女孩子的脸虽然都是同胚的，但是有的正则性好一点，所以这部分女孩子的脸就格外好看。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The end of this semester&amp;rsquo;s FINAL EXAM has come, and at last I could try to make time to complete this blog. This will be my first time to write a maths blog in English. I&amp;rsquo;ll translate it into Chinese later. Sounds odd&amp;hellip; Why don&amp;rsquo;t I write it in Chinese at very first, but force myself to use English pretending to be a native English speaker? Oh, it is said that maths majors are all somehow masochists. Most of them, anyway. You know, &amp;ldquo;No pain no gain.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
