<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on Offline Blog</title>
        <link>https://realyezhihao.github.io/en/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on Offline Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>Zhihao Ye</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 23:51:46 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://realyezhihao.github.io/en/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Hello World</title>
        <link>https://realyezhihao.github.io/en/posts/hello-world/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 23:51:46 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://realyezhihao.github.io/en/posts/hello-world/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://realyezhihao.github.io/en/posts/hello-world/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Hello World" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This site, established on 30th Dec. 2022, is hosted directly from a GitHub repository with the help of GitHub Pages. Generator Hexo and theme Hiya were adopted at very first, and the site was in rough compared to how it looks now. Later something upset me a lot and I almost gave up this site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently one of my old school friends has started blogging on his WeChat official account, which inspired me to rebuild and restart the site. It took me more than twenty hours to finish this work. This time I chose generator Hugo and theme Stack. I followed a zigzag course, as I&amp;rsquo;m not an expert in front-end design, and those documents in full English were difficult for me. Fortunately everything was completed and the site seems in good condition, at least currently. It&amp;rsquo;s no doubt that this blog is no match for platforms like Weibo, Zhihu and WeChat in SEO, but that&amp;rsquo;s what makes it a drift bottle and I like this. In addition, the URL won&amp;rsquo;t change since I have no money to buy a custom realm name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The about page written one year ago is as followed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;高中的时候就考虑过建立个人网站，但迫于个人知识狭隘和学业繁忙一直没实操。&lt;br&gt;
最近形政课开展一个调研课题，没地方发放我的调查问卷，于是建了一个网站来推广。&lt;br&gt;
以上是本站诞生的“导火索”了。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;作为计算机二级都没过的小白，开发这个网站可谓“溯洄从之，道阻且长”。&lt;br&gt;
本人没系统读过计算机，也不懂什么前端后端，就是偶尔折腾着玩儿。&lt;br&gt;
这两天我看了网上各种鱼龙混杂的信息，走了很多弯路。最后的网站是基于GitHub和Hexo实现。&lt;br&gt;
之所以把网站部署在GitHub上，最主要是因为它免费。&lt;br&gt;
另外，我很看好GitHub。它作为目前全球最大的&lt;del&gt;同性交友平台&lt;/del&gt;代码开源平台，无数程序设计者的智慧在其中凝结。&lt;br&gt;
“开源”对任何求知者都有着致命的诱惑。你的身旁将有无数志同道合者，你们将屹立于巨人的肩膀上。&lt;br&gt;
在任何年代，只要存在知识分享，“开源”就永不过时。&lt;br&gt;
我建立本站时主要的考量是稳定，GitHub的开源性就是它可持续的保障。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;比起外部环境变化，我更担心“内部敌人”的瓦解。&lt;br&gt;
如果哪天本人心态爆炸，永不更新，那这个小站岂不会遗失在互联网的烟海里？&lt;br&gt;
哎无所谓了，人本就是“寄蜉蝣于天地，渺沧海之一粟”。&lt;br&gt;
能来这里的都是有缘人，毕竟我既不是技术大牛，又没做过什么推广。&lt;br&gt;
诸位能光临本寒舍，不胜感激。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
